Guide to the Franklin Toker Papers, 1964-2017 UA.90.F108
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, 1986-2008; II.
  - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, 1986 Edition, 1986-1995; 1.
    - Drafts and Publication
      - Remarketing Pittsburgh Book (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Draft, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
  - Pittsburgh: A New Portrait, 2008; 2.
    This subseries primarily contains neighborhood and general research. The general research files explore Pittsburgh's development since the 1980s to identify changes between the 1986 edition and 2008. The subseries also contains photos of Pittsburgh.
    - Neighborhoods and Buildings
      - Aliquippa Research (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Allegheny County Airport Research (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Allegheny Observatory Research (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Beechwood Boulevard and Woodland Road Research (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Bethel Park Home of Greek Relief Research (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Beulah Presbyterian Church Research (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Bigelow Research (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Braddock Research (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Buildings Destroyed Since 1986 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Calvary Episcopal Church Research (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Camaham – Sellers Italianate Mansion Research (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Carnegie Library Braddock Research (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Carnegie Library Legacy Research (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Carnie Furnace Research (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Cartographic and View Traditions (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Cathedral of Learning Research (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - C.C. Mellor Library Research (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Census in 2000, June 2002 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Charles Schwab Mansion in Braddock Research (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Church of the Good Shepard, Hazelwood Research (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Civic Arena Research (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Color belts (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Conversations Research (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Crawford Square Research (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Donora, Mon Valley and John Woods House Research (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Early Settlers: South Hills Research (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Ebeneezer Baptist Research (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Edgar Thomson Steel Works Research (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Episcopal Church of the Ascension Research (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Evergreen Hamlet Research (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Forbes Field Research (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - FORE Systems Research (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Fox Chapel Golf Club Research (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - Frederick Sauer House Research (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Frick Building and other Research (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Golden Triangle- Old Views Research (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Guinner-Harter House Research (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - H.C. Frick Building and Frick Information (Box 12, Folder 30-32)
      - Highland Towers Research (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - The Hill and the Bluff Research (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Hindu-Jain Temple Research (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - Historical Pittsburgh Research (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - Holly Houses Research (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - Holy Trinity Serbian Orthodox Church Research (Box 12, Folder 38)
      - Homestead Works Research (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - Homewood Cemetery Research (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - Homewood, Wilkins House Information (Box 12, Folder 41-43)
      - Hornbostel Research (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Housing Initiatives Research (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Inclines Research (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Industry Research (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Inland East of Pittsburgh Research (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Inland South of Pittsburgh Research (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - John Frew House Research (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Kennywood Research (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Key Changes in Pittsburgh (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Landscapes Research (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - "La Tourelle" Research (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Lightener and Shaw Houses Research (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Longue Vine Club Research (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Lower Fifth Avenue Storefronts Research (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Lower Hill Research (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Mckees Rocks Bridge Research (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Mckees Rocks Research (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Meier House Research (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Mesta (George and Perle) House Research (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Millionaire Rows Research (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - Mount Lebanon and Mission Hills Research (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Mudge House Research (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Murals Research (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - Natrona Research (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Neighborhoods Research (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Neill Log House Research (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - New Granada Theater Research (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - Newington Research (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Nicola Research (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - Nicholas Way House Research (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - The Ohio Valley and Mckees Rocks Research (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Oliver Miller House, South Park Research (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - Osterling Research (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - Outside Pittsburgh Research (Box 13, Folder 34)
      - P&LE Yards Research (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Parkway East-Wilkinburg Research (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Pennsylvania Turnpike Bridge Research (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Pfeifer House Research (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - Pittsburgh Entrepreneurs (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - Pittsburgh International Airport Research (Box 13, Folder 40)
      - Pittsburgh Life Research (Box 13, Folder 41)
      - Pittsburgh Model Research (Box 13, Folder 42)
      - Pittsburgh Suburbs Research (Box 13, Folder 43)
      - Pittsburgh Technology Center Research (Box 13, Folder 44)
      - The Presley Neville House in Woodville Research (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - Rachel Carson House Research (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Redevelopment Blunders Research (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - Restoration Research (Box 13, Folder 48)
      - Richard King Mellon Hall of Science Research (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - Rising by the Rivers Research (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Riverside Developments Research (Box 13, Folder 51)
      - Sacred Heart Church Research (Box 13, Folder 52)
      - Saint Bernard's Church in Mt. Lebanon Research (Box 13, Folder 53)
      - Saint John's Greek Catholic Church Research (Box 13, Folder 54)
      - Saint Luke's Episcopal Research (Box 13, Folder 55)
      - Schenley Park Research (Box 13, Folder 56)
      - Secondary Changes in Pittsburgh (Box 13, Folder 57)
      - Shadyside and Squirrel Hill Research (Box 13, Folder 58)
      - Speyer House Research (Box 13, Folder 59)
      - Spirit of the Hill Research (Box 13, Folder 60)
      - Sprawl and Downtown Development Research (Box 13, Folder 61)
      - Squirrel Hill and Greenfield Research (Box 13, Folder 62)
      - Sri Venkateswara Temple Research (Box 13, Folder 63)
      - Steinburg House Research (Box 13, Folder 64)
      - Steps in Pittsburgh Research (Box 13, Folder 65)
      - Sunnyledge Research (Box 13, Folder 66)
      - Swan Acres Research (Box 13, Folder 67)
      - Terrace Village Research (Box 13, Folder 68)
      - Thornburgh Research (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Tony Buba Research (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Transportation Research (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Urban Planners Research (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Vandergrift Research (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Venturi House Research (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Village of Shadyside Research (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - West End Bridge Research (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Westinghouse Air-Brake Factory Complex Research (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Westinghouse Bridge Research (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Wilpin Hall Research (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - General Research
      - The Art Bulletin, June 1976 – March 1985 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Humanities Magazine, March/April 199 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Journal of the Society of Architectural Historians, May 1983 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - New Pittsburgh Research (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait: Changes Research (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait: Unused Research, July 2008 (Box 14, Folder 18-20)
      - Pittsburgh Details Not Used, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Pittsburgh Factoids (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Pittsburgh History (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Pittsburgh History (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
      - Pittsburgh Research Needing Categories (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Photographs
      - Architectural Photos of Pittsburgh (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Civic Photographs of Pittsburgh (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Commercial Photographs of Pittsburgh (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Domestic Photographs of Pittsburgh (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - North Side Photos (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Oakland Photos (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait CD photo (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 1 and Introduction Final Images (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 2 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 3 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 4 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 5 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 6 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 7 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 8 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 9 Final Images (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 9 Alternative Images (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Display Copies (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Image Log (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Permissions and Photos, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Photos, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
      - Pittsburgh Photos (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 1 (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 2 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 3 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 4 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 5 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 6 (Box 16, Folder 14-15)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 7 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Chapter 7 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
      - Pittsburgh Photos Used (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Pittsburgh Religious Photos (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - South Side Photos (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Urbanism Photos of Pittsburgh (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Fallingwater Rising, 2003; III.
  In 2003, Dr. Toker published Fallingwater Rising: Frank Lloyd Wright, E. J. Kaufmann, and America's Most Extraordinary House. This series contains book drafts, research files, correspondence, lectures, and other publications that focus on specific aspects of the book and Fallingwater.
  - Drafts, 2003; 1.
    This subseries consists of both early and edited drafts of the Fallingwater Rising book. Also present are illustrations, chapter openers, and a copy of the completed book.
    - Fallingwater Rising Early Draft (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 1 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 2 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 3 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 4 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 5 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 6 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 7 (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 8 (Box 17, Folder 16-18)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 9 (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 9 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 10 (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
    - Fallingwater Rising Draft 11 (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
    - Illustration Notes (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Chapter Openers (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Draft Notes (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
    - Fallingwater Rising draft (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
    - Fallingwater Rising First Draft (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
    - Fallingwater Rising First Draft (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Fallingwater Rising Second Draft (Box 19, Folder 3-5)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 1 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 2 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 3 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 4 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 5 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 6 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 7 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 8 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 9 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 10 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 11 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Chapter 12 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Fallingwater Rising: Epilogue, Acknowledgments, Index, Sources (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Fallingwater Rising Illustration Notes (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Fallingwater Rising Book, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Other Publications, 2.
    This subseries is made up of articles regarding Fallingwater authored by Toker during his extensive research on the house. These articles either contributed to or aided in the research for his Fallingwater Rising book.
    - Making Fallingwater Rising (Box 19, Folder 21-22)
    - Fabricating Fallingwater: Notes on Book (Box 19, Folder 23-24)
    - The Most Famous House in the World draft by Franklin Toker, July 1998 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - The Most Famous House in the World draft by Franklin Toker, August 1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Setting Manuscript (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
  - Photographs, 3.
    The images and other media in this subseries include photographs of Fallingwater, as well as other locations affiliated with Frank Lloyd Wright. Such photos have been used in research for and the production of Fallingwater Rising. Also included are proofs of the book jacket design. There are some photos that are not identified.
    - Avery Blueprints and Notes (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Avery Photos and Notes (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Bullock's Wilshire Building Photos (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - CDs on Fallingwater (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - CDs on Other Locations (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Ennis House Photos (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Eugene A. Gilmore House Photos (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Fallingwater Rising Cover Art (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Fallingwater Photos (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Fallingwater Photos used in Fallingwater Rising (Box 20, Folder 16-17)
    - Fallingwater Photos with Kaufmann Family (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Floppy Disks of Fallingwater (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Getty Museum Photos (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Griffith Observatory Photos (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Hollyhock House Photos (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Kaufmann's Department Store (Box 61, Item 1)
    - Kaufmann Family Photos (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Kaufmann Palm Spring House Photos (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Kentucky Knob Photos (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Lovell House Photos (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Photos of Blueprints, Drawings, and Newspapers (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Photos of Other Houses (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Robert M. Lamp House Photos (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Salk Institute Photos (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Unknown Location Photos (Box 21, Folder 12-25)
    - Xeroxes of Final Photo Selection for Fallingwater Rising (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Research, 4.
    This subseries contains the extensive research done for the Fallingwater Rising book. These files pertain to such subjects as the house itself, the Kaufmann family, Frank Lloyd Wright, and the geographic area. Several of these files include copies of archival material from other repositories.
    - Alternative Photos for Fallingwater Rising (Box 21, Folder 27-32)
    - Analysis of the Master Terrace at Fallingwater by Pennsylvania Conservancy Mill Run (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Annals of Architecture: A House called Fallingwater, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Architecture Research (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Bear Run Nature Reserve (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Bear Run Plants (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Blume Research (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Coal and Coke in Fayette (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, Bushwell Brown, 1927-1945 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1913-1934 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1938-1940 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1941-1951 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright, 1952-1959 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright with Albert Einstein and Others, 1930-1958 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Kaufmann, 1934-1952 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - The Dead Man: Frank Lloyd Wright as Fortune's Ebb (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - The Deed (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Drawings (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
    - Drawings and Correspondence on Purchasing Them (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Fallingwater Archive Notes, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Fallingwater Book, Prologue (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Fallingwater: The Engineering and Construction of a Masterpiece by Kremer (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Fallingwater Newsletter (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Fallingwater Research papers Chinese Edition, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Fallingwater Research papers Chinese Edition, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Fallingwater Rising Chapter 3 Research (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
    - Fallingwater Rising Chapter 4 Research (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Fallingwater Rising Chapter 5 Research (Box 23, Folder 5-7)
    - Fayette County Facts (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Fayette County in 1935 Research (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Fayette County Today Research (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Research (Box 23, Folder 11-14)
    - General Kaufmann Collection Research (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - History of Fayette County Research (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - History of the Land Research (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - History of Mill Run Research (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Important Fallingwater Research (Box 23, Folder 19-20)
    - Interviews on Fallingwater, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Junior Article, February 17, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Kahlo Research (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Kaufmann and Judaism Research (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Kaufmann Department Store Research (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
    - Kaufmann Family Research (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Kaufmann's Paper Articles (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Kaufmann Personal Information (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
    - Kaufmann Research (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Kaufmann Store Research (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Liliane Kaufmann Research (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Maps of Land (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings and Notes (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - The Most Famous House in the World Draft, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - "Mr. Kaufmann, Mr. Wright, and the Origins of Fallingwater" (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - New York Museum of Modern Art Research (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Pennsylvania Geology (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Photocopies and Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Prince and California Research (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Publisher Information and Research (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    - Raising Fallingwater Chapter 6 Research (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Raising Fallingwater Chapter 7 Research (Box 25, Folder 4-6)
    - Raising Fallingwater Chapter 8 Research (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Raising Fallingwater Chapter 9 Research (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
    - Raising Fallingwater Epilogue Research (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Raising Fallingwater Bibliography Research (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Rivera Research (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Robinson Research (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Student Report on Fallingwater, Spring 1999 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Student Report on Phenomenon of Fallingwater, Spring 1999 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Toker Observations on Drawings (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Various Research and Sources, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 17-18)
    - Viktor Hammer Research (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Wright Research (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
    - Yesteryear in Ohiopyle Research (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Lectures, 5.
    These files contain the text of several lectures presented by Dr. Toker pertaining to various aspects of Fallingwater, as well as notes on the 1999 Fallingwater Seminar.
    - Fallingwater Lectures (Box 26, Folder 5-10)
    - Notes on Fallingwater Seminar, January -April, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 6.
    This subseries holds research and publication related correspondence pertaining to Fallingwater Rising.
    - Agent Information and Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
    - Toker Correspondence, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Florence Duomo Project, 1970-2017; IV.
  This series contains the vast amount of research and writing completed by Dr. Toker on the Duomo in Florence, Italy. Included are drafts of the first two volumes of the project. The first, On Holy Ground: Liturgy, Architecture and Urbanism in the Cathedral and the Streets of Medieval Florence, covers the origins of the Duomo's architecture and was published in 2009. The second book is titled Archaeological Campaigns Below the Florence Duomo and Baptistery, 1895-1980, which covers the excavations below Santa Maria del Fiore and was published in 2012. There is also information about the other two volumes, Reconstructing the Cathedral and Baptistery of Florence in Late Antiquity and the Middle Ages and When Stones Speak: The Florence Duomo Excavations in the Light of History. In addition to writing drafts, this series also contains research files and correspondence.
  - On Holy Ground: Liturgy, Architecture and Urbanism in the Cathedral and the Streets of Medieval Florence, 2009; 1.
    This subseries details the first book of the Florence Duomo Project volumes, which looks into the origins of the architecture and design of the Cathedral. Included in this subseries are the book's appendices and a variety of drafts of the first volume.
    - Appendix I and II On Holy Ground Draft (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - On Holy Ground Early Draft (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - On Holy Ground Full Draft 1 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
    - On Holy Ground Rough Draft 1 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - On Holy Ground Rough Draft 2 (Box 27, Folder 7-10)
    - On Holy Ground Rough Drafts 3 (Box 27, Folder 11-13)
    - On Holy Ground Small Draft (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Archaeological Campaigns Below the Florence Duomo and Baptistery, 1895-1980, 2010; 2.
    This subseries contains two drafts of the second volume in the Duomo series, which pertains to the excavations and findings at Santa Maria del Fiore in Florence, Italy.
    - Archaeological Campaigns Rough Drafts (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
    - Archaeological Campaigns Rough Draft #2 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Reconstructing the Cathedral and Baptistery of Florence in Late Antiquity and the Middle Ages, 2016; 3.
    This subseries contains four drafts of the third volume of the Florence Duomo Project, which details the architecture of the Duomo by exploring its historical context.
    - Santa Reparata: Architectural History Draft (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Santa Reparata: The Architectural History Full Draft (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
    - Santa Reparata: The Architectural History Rough Draft #1 (Box 28, Folder 7-9)
    - Santa Reparata: The Architectural History Rough Drafts (Box 28, Folder 10-11)